district279.org 2014-12-17

# ISD 279 - Osseo Area Schools - Privacy

##  [ Privacy Statement](http://www.district279.org/privacy)

**Privacy Notice Information** (Tennessen Notice)

This notice addresses the collection, use, security of and access to information that may be obtained during your use of this website.

**Information Collected and How it is Used.** We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily participate in an activity that asks for information (e.g., filling out a Web form, registering for an event or participating in a survey). If you choose not to participate in these activities, your choice will in no way affect your ability to use any other feature of ISD 279 website or your ability to access the services of ISD 279. The situations where you may be asked to provide personal information include the following:

> **E-mail Lists.** If you sign up for one of our e-mail lists, we may ask for such information as contact information, e-mail address and similar information. The information you provide will be used to subscribe you to the e-mail list service and ensure that you receive the requested e-mail and other similar types of information. It may also be used for the purposes described in the section below entitled “Disclosure of Information.” If you subscribe to an e-mail list, specific information will be provided explaining how to unsubscribe from the e-mail list service. Please note that we will not offer your email address to anyone else.
> 
> **Web Forms and Surveys.** The ISD 279 website may provide the opportunity for you to complete forms and surveys, such as information request forms and feedback forms. The requested information may include such items as contact information, demographic information, areas of interest, your satisfaction with the services of ISD 279 and other similar types of information. The personal information you provide will be used only for such purposes as are described at the point of collection, such as to send information to you or to evaluate the success of ISD 279 programs. It may also be used for the purposes described in the section below entitled “Disclosure of Information.”
> 
> **Account Services.** The ISD 279 website may provide the opportunity for you to access account services, such as class registration, facility rental, food service account balance and online purchases from a school store. The requested information may include such items as contact information, demographic information, password information and payment information. The information will be used for the purposes described at the point of collection, such as to access your account and process payment. It may also be used for the purposes described in the section below entitled “Disclosure of Information.”
> 
> **Electronic Access Data.** In addition to the personal information described above, our system collects server log data which may include an IP address, the type of browser and operating system used, the time of day visited, the pages viewed and the information requested through searches. We aggregate this data and use it for statistical purposes, helping us to ascertain, for example, the amount of interest in portions of our website and ways to improve the navigation and content of our website.

**Disclosure of Information.** Electronic access data, including cookies, are classified as private data on individuals or nonpublic data. The data may be shared with employees and agents of ISD 279 for the purposes stated in the above sections. ISD 279 may not disclose this information to third parties without your written consent or court order, except for the following purposes:

  1. To the Commissioner of the Minnesota Department of Administration for the purpose of evaluating electronic government services;
  2. To another government entity to prevent unlawful intrusions into government electronic systems; or
  3. As otherwise provided by law.

The identifiable personal information you provide through e-mail lists, Web forms and surveys, account services and other uses of the ISD 279 website is classified as public, private, or non-public data. The data may be shared with employees and agents of ISD 279 as necessary to provide the specific service requested, to track the success of programs, to complete required state and federal reports and to maintain the functioning and security of ISD 279 systems.

To the extent such data is classified as educational or personnel data, the data may be classified as private data. ISD 279 may not disclose private data, except summary data, without the prior written consent of the subject of the data, or subject’s parent or guardian, except as provided in ISD 279 Policies No. 406 — Public and Private Personnel Data and No. 515 — Protection and Privacy of Education Records. Copies of these policies may be obtained from Sue Weber at (763) 391-7080 or may be viewed at [www.district279.org/who/policies.cfm](http://www.district279.org/who/policies.cfm).

Data that you provide that is not otherwise classified as private or non-public data pursuant to state or federal law will be public data that ISD 279 must make accessible to any member of the public upon request. For example, non-identifiable summary information is classified as public data and may be shared with third parties. Such aggregate summary data will not allow others to identify you.

ISD 279 does not rent or, as otherwise provided by law, sell your personal information to third parties.

**Access and Correction of Personal Information.** You can review any personal information we collect about you. You may recommend changes to your personal information you believe to be inaccurate or incomplete by submitting a written request that describes the nature of the error. If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact us. In all cases, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.

Contact Information: Tim Wilson at (763) 391-7160 or [wilsont@district279.org](mailto:finsnessl@district279.org)
